Okay. Well, let's give this a shot. So,
um, important thing to know, as the
naming convention goes, it goes for the
dog API, it's dog-b. For the advice API,
it's advice-BT. For the joke API, it's
joke-b or output um or image in the case
of the dog. So, let's add those event
listeners first. So, we'll say
document.query selector and we'll look
for dog-ashbutton.
and we'll add an event listener. We're
going to add a click event listener. And
what do we want to do? We want to call
the get dog function. That's when they
click it. And I'm going to duplicate
that. So here um when they do the advice
button, I want to call get advice.
And here when they do the joke button,
I want to call get joke. Now I'm going
to write them. The first one I'm going
to write is get dog. And I'm going to do
this first using the then chain and then
everything else I'm going to do async a
weight because that's the one I prefer.
But just so that I can demonstrate both,
we're going to do both here. So the
first thing we need to do is we need to
write get dog. So we'll say const get
dog equals a function.
And inside of the function we need to
call fetch. And what are we fetching?
Well, let's check the readme. Here in
the readme, it's got this link to the
dog image. And actually, if we click it,
we can see what gets returned. And you
can see that it is an object that has
the keyword message. And all of that in
the message has um the URL to the image.
So if we want to set the source to that,
then we just need to access it. So we'll
say fetch. Well, not that URL.
Got to actually copy the URL.
Fetch from this URL.
And what do we want to do? Well, um once
we have it, we want to take the results
of what we got and convert it to JSON.
And that is an asynchronous function.
And remember, if you wrapped this in
curly braces, then you have to use the
keyword return because I did it on all
on one line and no curly braces. I don't
need the keyword return. And then I'm
going to say then and what do I want to
do here? I want to take the result um
and I'm going to call it data and I'm
going to display it on the page. So, I'm
going to say document.query selector.
And this is the dog. So, we're going to
say dog uh we're going to look for the
image that has the ID of dog img. And
we're going to set it source
equal to the data we got back dot mess.
Let me move my image
message.
So, if we save that,
um we're saying set it equal to this URL
that we get back. And if we come here
and we click get dog,
let's inspect and see if we got an
error. Uncut error cannot access get dog
before initialization. And I apologize.
If we want to attach get dog to this
function, we actually have to put it
before. So we're going to take all of
these
and move it under get dog and save it.
Now if we click get dog, tada, there's
our dog who's a good boy. All right. Um,
so that's get dog and that's how you'd
fetch that. Well, let's do advice. And
I'm going to do this using async8. So
I'll say const get advice and I'm going
to set it equal to async
function.
And here I need to get the data. So I'm
going to say const get um const uh
response equals
await fetch. And where are we fetching?
Well, let's go check. It says go to this
advice API. So, I'm going to copy that.
I'm going to paste it here. And I'm
going to get the response. Well, now I
need as JSON data. So, I'm going to say
const JSON data equals await
res.json.
Okay. So, what I'm doing is I'm fetching
the data and then I'm turning it into
JSON data that I can use. I'm going to
click on this link to see what I'm going
to get back. If I come over here and I
see that I get back an object that has a
key of slip and inside of it, it has
another object which has an key of
advice.
And what I can do because this returns
JSON, I can actually dstructure it and
grab slip out of it. So this returns an
object and I can say go into the object
and grab out slip. Once you have that
then I want you to query selector the
page and look for um advice
dashoutput
and we're going to set its inner text
equal to slip advice.
So notice because we got back an object
and then I destructured it and grabbed
out slip. Um now I can go into that
object and grab out advice.
So if we save this and we come over to
our running code, we can click get dog
and we get a dog. We click get advice
and it says don't be afraid of silly
ideas. We can click get advice again. It
says when hugging, hug with both arms
and apply reasonable affectionate
pressure. And there you go. We can now
get advice. Now the last one we want to
do is just this get joke. And actually
you will notice that the code is going
to be strikingly similar to this. So
let's come over here and I have set a
bunch of flags on this API so that it
avoids anything that's not safe for
work, not religious, not political, not
racist, not sexist or explicit. And um I
set the type of joke we get back to be a
oneliner um or something that doesn't
have a question and then a response. So,
I'm going to copy that. That's what I've
set on this API. And you can actually go
look at the documentation for it and it
explains how to set all of that. Um, but
I'm going to come over here to my script
tag and I am going to duplicate this
code and I'm going to switch this from
saying get advice to saying get joke.
And here I'm going to just swap the URL
and save it. And if I actually click on
this, I can see that what it gives me
back is it gives me back an object that
has a joke attribute. So I can actually
dstructure it and just grab the joke
directly. And then here instead of going
to advice output, I'm going to go to
joke output and instead of setting it to
slip.vice, I'm going to set it equal to
the joke. So now, and I apologize, I
don't control these jokes. I tried to
with the flags. We I have no idea what
jokes are going to show up. So, I click
get dog. Boom. Dog picture. I click get
advice. Boom. Be brave. Even if you're
not, pretend to be. No one can tell the
difference. Then I click random joke.
And it says I sentence you to the
maximum punishment. Me thinking, please
be death. Please be death. Judge, learn
Java. Me. Dang it. And there you have
it. Now you get a random joke. Um, and
you can get another one.
And this is now a fully functional
thing. And you have successfully used
fetch.